if you're a dedicated deadlifter looking
for your new trusty Excalibur in your
home gym look no further than the rep
Fitness Hades deadlift bar this bar has
a diameter of 27 millimeters 15.7 inch
loading sleeves you can really pack on
some plates and it's competitively
priced this barbell is designed to go
Toe to Toe with the top dead lifting
bars out there but how does it actually
stack up let's find out today let's get
to it
[Music]
all right
what's good everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I've got the rep Fitness Hades
deadlift bar in this video today I'm
going to tell you everything there is to
know about this barbell specifically
we're going to talk about some money
you're talking about some pros and cons
and of course who should or maybe should
not purchase this barbell before I do
that though I gotta let y'all know we've
reviewed a ton of barbells on barbin.com
and we went ahead and made a best list
of all of our top choices that are on
the market so if you want to check that
out just go ahead and Google barbend
best barbells that list is going to pull
right up for you you can find out for
yourself which ones we like the best and
honestly you might be surprised which
one cracks that number one spot
foreign
okay so as the name suggests the Hades
deadlifting bar is in fact a dedicated
deadlifting Bar And for those who aren't
familiar with what a dead lifting bar is
well you came to the right place because
I'm going to tell you really quick all
right so generally speaking deadlifting
bars typically have a thinner diameter
than a power bar and multi-purpose bars
you're also going to notice more whip in
the shaft meaning there's going to be
more flexion especially as you're
lifting in the 400 pound range and maybe
even higher if you can pull that much
one more thing here is that you're also
typically going to notice that the
spacing between the knurling is also
going to be spaced out further and
there's not going to be a center
knurling that way you know you're
avoiding you know shredding up your
shins as you're going to lift your
weight and you're going to notice all
these things with the Hades all right so
starting with the diameter this is 27
millimeters it's going to really allow
you to get a really solid grip as you go
to get positioned for your lifts and
speaking of the grip the knurling right
here is a mount and style knurling so
each and every single one of these
points right here on this cross hatching
pattern sticks up as a mountain wood and
it's pretty aggressive so it's really
going to allow you to get really sticky
grip but it's not going to be too
abrasive to where you know it's leaving
a bunch of indentions and you know
causing your calluses if you have them
to kind of rip open or maybe you can
create new ones honestly it's really
really solid as I mentioned you are
going to notice more whip with this
barbell
probably not until you get around 400
pounds of weight but you know that extra
flexion is going to allow you to lift
from a higher position and probably
allow you to you know pull better I
guess you could say it's priced at right
around 370 dollars which honestly is a
pretty solid price tag considering the
overall quality especially since the
fact that this is a cerakote finish now
you do have DuraCoat loading sleeves and
I'll explain what that is in just a
minute but you know cerakote offers a
high level of protection so honestly 370
bucks it's a pretty solid deal now that
being said not everybody has 370 dollars
that you know they can spend on a
barbell that's only for dead lifting you
know this isn't a versatile bar you can
go and get plenty of other barbells I
mean rep Fitness has the Colorado bar
which is cheaper than this one and you
can you know hit any style lift that you
want and then plus you know really the
only other thing here is that it's not
stainless steel stainless steel has the
highest level of protection from
corrosion cerakote is still really nice
you know don't don't get it twisted this
is still you know really solid it's
still going to protect it for a long
time it's just not stainless steel and
then lastly I just want to take one
second and talk about the loading
sleeves this might not be a con for
everybody but you know if you're
somebody who is in fact you know really
really strong and lifting some you know
eye-popping weight the loading sleeves
measure 15.75 inches now that is longer
than you know a lot of other dedicated
dead lifting bars but there's plenty of
standard barbells that have a little bit
longer of loading sleeves and that's
going to allow you to maybe tack on you
know one more weight plate so that's
just something you need to keep in mind
[Music]
okay so once again the rep Fitness Hades
deadlift bar is going to run you right
around 370 bucks and that's including
shipping due to the fact that this you
know that is included and that this is a
cerakote barbell I think that's a really
solid price tag now if you want to go
down a cheaper route another Barb rail
that we're really high on is the bells
of Steel bare naked powerlifting bar 2.0
it's going to run around 220 bucks but
you know big butt with that one is that
it is bare steel which bare steel is
known to rust and it will rust on you so
you will have to take you know more
precautions with it and clean it more
frequently and plus it's gonna be better
off if you have you know a climate
controlled room to kind of help prevent
that a little bit so you know that's you
know kind of the kicker with that it's
just you're gonna have to take better
care of a bare steel barbell let's
expand a little bit on these comparisons
and with the Rogue Ohio deadlift bar
honestly I think these bars are pretty
much neck and neck and on paper you know
that original price tag with the Ohio
deadlift bar they're the same price tag
but with Rogue you do in fact have to
pay for shipping so it winds up being
more expensive and you know pretty much
everybody's
golden deadlift bar is the Texas power
deadlifting bar right well their
cerakote version is 440 bucks including
shipping yes you have longer loading
sleeves if you're somebody who's you
know upper echelon you know 99th
percentile of dead lifters that might be
worth it for you but
that's still you know a significant jump
in price right there so all in all 370
bucks for this barbell I think it's
really solid price tag
[Music]
all right so I just want to expand on
the construction one more time really
quick with the Hades deadlift bar
remember this is a cerakote bar but the
loading sleeves are DuraCoat so for
those who don't know rep is using this
DuraCoat loading sleeve on all the new
barbells right now and basically this is
just a chemical process that they're
using on the loading sleeves to make
them more tough and resilient now that's
a good thing you definitely don't want
things to be brittle and weak and stuff
but something I forgot to mention in the
cons is actually that as you're loading
and unloading your weight
you're going to notice scratches I guess
you could call them on your loading
sleeves now what that is it's it's
because the loading sleeves are so tough
that they're actually pulling you know
material from the collars of the inside
of your weight plates now they mentioned
on their website you can kind of wipe it
off and those scratches will go away you
know I've tried that it works to an
extent but you know over time those
scratches are just kind of kind of gonna
be there and something you're gonna have
to deal with now it's not gonna you know
cause the bar to deteriorate or you know
anything like that it's just not going
to be as you know aesthetically pleasing
I guess you could say now remember with
this bar you do have a 27 millimeter
diameter on the shaft right here it's
going to allow you to get you know a
really solid grip and just really you
know get your hands completely around
that barbell and since this is thinner
it's going to have more flexion under
loads and allow you to lift from you
know a higher position especially as
you're lifting you know eye popping
weight speaking of eye popping weight
you can load up to 1500 pounds on this
bar and it has a tensile rating of 190
000 PSI which for dead lifting that is
you know plenty strong it's definitely
going to get the job done and last thing
I want to talk about is the actual
dimensions all right so this bar
measures 91.7 inches in length with
15.75 inch loading sleeves so the actual
bar is longer than you know your typical
barbell but the loading sleeves actually
a little bit shorter than a lot of other
barbells one that comes to mind is the
rep Fitness Double Black Diamond all
right so the shaft is longer and thinner
so it has more flexion but you know with
the Double Black Diamond those loading
sleeves are a little bit longer so you
can actually you know load more weight
with that other barbell all right so I
just want to show you all some stuff up
close with the Hades so I really like
what rep is doing with their end caps
right here metal end cap and it just
kind of has you know adds to the you
know Greek mythology they're kind of
using especially with you know some of
the
designs right here and everything it's
just pretty cool you shouldn't really
have to you know take these loading
sleeves off to clean them but if you
ever need to there's a little snap ring
right here get some snap ring pliers you
know just pop it out and take the sleeve
off wipe it down all that stuff now I
don't know if you can really tell right
now I've already wiped it off as they
you know kind of tell you to do but with
this DuraCoat sleeve since it's so tough
it's actually going to pull some
material from the inside of your weight
plates and you can might be able to see
some scratches right here but just get a
rag wipe it down it takes a little bit
of elbow grease but it definitely helps
you out now these are smooth loading
sleeves there's not any type of grouped
pattern right here typically with you
know barbells that feature that it's
going to help keep those white plates in
the original placement
it's not that big of a deal you have
weight collars anyways definitely toss
those on it'll help you out but one more
thing here I like how this tapers down
and it makes it really easy for you to
load and unload your plates and plus
without having that grouped pattern that
kind of helps too so as we move further
in right here you do have bronze
bushings and honestly I was a little bit
surprised by how much this loading
sleeve spins same thing with the other
one it's not gonna you know negatively
affect you bronze bushings are designed
to be used with you know bars that are
used for power lifting movements you
know like this one right here so that's
just kind of the standard now with the
knurling you'll notice you only have one
set of neural markings ipf standard you
know it's hand placement and everything
but as far as the actual knurling goes
I'm a big fan of it it's pretty sharp
it's a sharp Mountain early remember all
these points stick up like a mountain
but since there's so many of them kind
of bunched in together they don't and
they don't stand as tall as some other
ones it's not going to really you know
tear up your hands it feels pretty good
at the end of the day now you do not
have any type of cinnamon rolling right
here here I personally like that you
don't need that with this kind of bar
and since the actual knurling right here
is spaced out further than you know a
lot of other barbells not really with
reps but with a lot of other ones you
know that allows you to get your legs in
between the knurling right here and
prevent you from you know kind of
ripping up your shins you definitely
don't want that remember
the sleeves are DuraCoat as I mentioned
but the actual shaft is cerakote and
that's the only coating that this bar is
available in now hang tight one quick
second I'm gonna go pull out another one
of reps barbells and just kind of show
you the difference in the dimensions all
right so I went ahead and pulled out the
Double Black Diamond from rep Fitness
this is their new flagship power bar and
as you can see I'm assuming you can see
the Hades is longer overall and that's
because the actual shaft for both of
these are different all right so I got
my trusty tape measure let's go ahead
and measure these out really quick start
with the Double Black Diamond
and this is right around 51 inches
as you can see it's basically right
there 51 inches now with the Hades this
is about 56 55 and a half about 55 and a
half right there so because of that
extra length right here and the fact
that it's thinner remember this is 27
millimeters in diameter with double
black diamond it's 29 millimeters now
because this one's thinner and it's
longer you're gonna notice more whip
it's going to be more flexible
especially as you're you know lifting
super heavy weight now with the Double
Black Diamond you know that extra
thickness and the fact that it's shorter
it's going to make it more rigid more
stiff overall so you know it kind of
obviously depends what you're looking
for right now so if you're looking for a
dedicated deadlifting bar you're
definitely going to want to go after the
Hades now I think this barbell is ideal
for anybody who's a dedicated dead
lifter or you know maybe you're a
competitor and you're looking for a bar
to practice with that meets the ipf
standards because this does on the flip
side though you know if you're not a
dedicated dead lifter and you know
really care for all that you can
definitely go find yourself a normal
power lifting bar because it's going to
be able to get the job done or maybe
even a multi-purpose bar that could be
used across all your lifts in your home
gym
[Music]
uh that's all I got for y'all today on
the rep Fitness Hades deadlifting boy
now this is obviously a niche barbell
designed for one specific style of
lifting but you know if that's what
you're looking for I think this is a
really solid option it's competitively
priced and honestly it's one of my
favorite deadlifting bars on the market
thanks for watching y'all hope this
video was really helpful and I was able
to break down everything you need to
know about this barbell as always I say
it all the time I'm going to say it
again stay on the lookout for my next
video but for now head over to
barbin.com so we have a full written
article about this barbell all you got
to do is search bar Bend rep Fitness
Hades deadlifting Bar review it's going
to pull right up for you you can go over
everything we talked about here today
I'll catch y'all next time
[Music]
foreign